Coach, always great to see you. Thanks
for letting us be in your office, man.
>> Yeah, it's awesome, man. Good to have
you here. Too many times in the head
coach's office. You're like, I don't
know.
>> Yeah, who know? Yeah, I was going to
say, man, getting cut is a tough deal up
in here. Uh, so what I'd say, coach, is
this has been a crazy off seasonason for
you. Two new coordinators, a huge all in
free agency. Obviously, draft's coming
up. Where do you think the team is at
right now heading into the draft?
>> Well, you know, change, that's each year
that's going to be the one. And so this
year a lot, you know, obviously with the
free agency coaching side and now
>> one more piece to come, you know, with
the draft coming, but here on April
20th, this is our first time of getting
everybody together. And what we'll need
to see in this time is how does the
team, that chemistry, that development,
all of them together. But man, we're
really pumped. Um, we really like where
we're at and uh we're excited to get
rolling.
>> I'm sure, man, it's always exciting with
the new season. One thing I'm pretty
sure you're excited about, too, is kind
of you got two new coordinators. Yep.
got to kind of learn what they're about,
what the system is. How fun was that
process for you kind of saying, "Oh,
this is how this defense works. This is
how this defensive end plays." What was
that process like for you?
>> Yeah, that was awesome. And uh it's one
of the um parts about the profession
that I love the most is how do you grow,
what's different, what changes, and
knowing that you can be in front of some
of those changes. And talking about like
Dante specifically, I thought systemwise
coming from Minnesota, what they've been
doing, I thought Logan, they were really
in front of some of the things in terms
of the checks, the adjustments they were
making at the line of scrimmage. I had
liked what I had seen from that group
and then getting to know him, the
teaching background that he has, uh, it
just really all came together for us.
>> Yeah. And I think the other cool thing
is like obviously you work with Adam
quite a bit. Like how do those
conversations with those guys like
affect the personnel side with free
agency with the draft coming up? Like
how does that affect your process with
the people in the building?
>> Right. When we got everybody on board,
um, David and Dante, staff-wise, the
first thing we did was have them present
to the scouts,
>> to the pro scouts, the college scouts,
this is the system. These are some of
the traits. This is what we'd be looking
for to see, is there anything changing
at a position? Is there anything
different that we would need to look
for? Um, and so those were the things
that we did right away. And so making
sure from the scouting side that we're
all, you know, speaking from the same
>> the same book. you know, so to speak,
uh, was really important. I thought like
Adam and the staff and the coaches have
just spent as much time as we could
through free agency and now through the
draft, so we're all like seeing it
exactly the same.
>> Yeah. And I think that's interesting you
bring up like the relationship there
because you bring in all these, you
know, big- time pass rushers, big time,
big time. And how does the free agency
period affect what you're doing with the
draft and your philosophy heading in?
Like I think that's always a fun kind of
conversation to have.
>> It is. And anytime you can go and really
feel comfortable to go play before the
draft, you know, you're really sitting
in a strong spot. And that's how we feel
today because you're not we have to get
this or we have to get that, we have to
get this. And so going into it, it
allows you um to add to the group and
that's such a cool piece to it. But
yeah, we're really excited about the
people that we added, different pieces,
some rushers, add a backer who's got
inside blitz technique, some corners,
obviously a tight end, and you know,
just different spots, running back, you
know, just different pieces to how we'd
go about it. And uh
>> we're able to resign some players, too,
which was a big deal for us. So, yeah,
we're excited with this group that we
have and then to add to it here in a
couple weeks. U we're pumped for that,
too.
>> Yeah. You talk about bringing new people
in and you're always talking about your
growth mindset and how you kind of
always want to evolve and change and be
the best version of yourself. How has
that impacted the way you evaluate these
guys coming out? It's like such a
different game, such a different process
for you. Can you talk about some of that
for us? I
>> think you want to find out like from a
player standpoint, what are the unique
things that player can bring to the team
>> and can they find spaces to do that over
and over again? And so like for instance
in your spot for the
>> people like all right this guy could run
block better than most everybody but
that was that was your superpower. And
so Mike and the staff here they they
came to find that out and recognize that
and then put you in the spots to allow
you to do your thing. Man I can get my
helmet wide and get run. I can knock
people out.
>> And so that type of skill
>> is really appreciated. And so as we're
going through the draft process, what
would the player do if they were here on
our team?
>> Who would they compete with? What would
that look like? How would we feature
them, whether it's offense or defense?
And Larry Iso is a big part of the
evaluations, too. He goes through a lot
of their tape during college special
teams or just offensively and
defensively, and how would they fit into
that role as well. And so when we put
all those together, that's why we love
the dialogue, you know, in terms of
getting ready for the draft.
>> Yeah. One of my favorite things about
playing for you, coach, honestly, was
your constant hunger for like this
superpower. And so, one of the things I
think people miss with the draft process
in general, it's not about always the
guy, but about it's about the role and
situation and development. How do you
ensure that you get the best the best
version of these guys once they're here
in the building?
>> Yeah, it's interesting that you bring
that up because right now, due to maybe
I don't know if this is the last COVID
year of class, there's players that have
five and six years of experience. Some
dudes are 26 years old.
>> And there's others that are in that
traditional three years and out. And so
there's this big, you know, levels of
experience to somebody who has lots of
experience may have started,
>> you know, over 50 55 games and then
others that may have had, you know, a
year and a half of starting being that
they were the only at college for three
years. But getting back to your initial
question is where do you think that
person can go to? where do you think
their traits can lead them to? And maybe
in year one, they may have this role,
but by year two, we'd expect them to get
to this spot. So, you have to have some
vision of what they can be. But, um, it
is interesting when you see the
different levels of experience because
if somebody's already 24, close to 25
coming in the NFL, they're close to
maybe where their ceiling is, where
others who may have only, you know, 21
and just getting rolling, like that's a
big space. And uh sometimes there's a
bigger gap that they can make up.
>> Is there anything to to your thought
process with that where it's like as a
coach, can I get this guy there? Like
and that's why we want him here because
we think he can actualize this
potential.
>> Yes. And that's to me then for me to
push to the coach say, okay, what's the
action you'll take to help him get
there? Yeah.
>> Because if you think they can all right,
what would that look like? And that's
why you the meetings with the players
can be so critical. You want to find out
what type of adversity have they
overcome, you know, in playing football
because like we know that's going to
happen 100% how hard it's going to be
and how do they overcome that and what
was the hardest thing to learn and skill
for them.
>> And so if they can articulate that and
say that then we know, okay, this is a
person that's already been through some
things and they know how to get better.
And if we can do that and have a
specific plan for them, man, does it
make the runway easier for them when
they get here. Hey, this is what we
think you can be. And oftentimes a
player may not even understand that
about themselves. Sure.
>> It's why so oftentimes we see somebody,
okay, how do you get drafted late or
undrafted and just take off?
>> This is the exact thing that we need you
to do and that can you do it at a really
high level, plan it, map it out for him,
and then see if we can take him there.
>> Coach, I could talk about this with you
all day, but I think the thing that
people want to know at home is like
draft spread. We got some adversity
happening in the building.
>> Chef Connor's moving on. Chef Brandon's
taken over. Yes.
>> What's the expect? I mean, it's a big
night, man. Conor used to do lobster
tales and flaming, all kinds of stuff.
What's Brandon's deal? And what's
>> I think Brandon's really going to be
dialed in. You need something to sustain
us, you know, because after that pick,
it's going to goes on for a long time.
So, I think pizza is definitely going to
be a big part of that.
>> Okay.
>> Um,
>> chicken wings, anything like that?
>> There should be that for sure. U, we've
got excellent ice cream sandwiches for
late Saturday. You do? You do? Yes. And
so those are just a few of the staples
uh that you want to make sure you have.
>> It's about the proper nutrition. Yes.
It's it's a marathon, not a sprint,
right?
>> That's right. And you want to make sure
you have just the right amounts of of
things as you're heading Newton through
the weekend, but come Thursday, I have
full confidence.
Brandon is going to be ready. He's been
practicing a lot, you know, this off
season. So, uh I've got full confidence
in him, dude.
>> Coach, good luck. Thanks so much, man.
Appreciate it. Thanks, Luke.